Guide to the Stanford University, International Relations Program, Honors Theses SC4-6526 SC4-6526
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Theses, 1978-1998; Accession ARCH_2005_278
  - Mijares, Veronica Weichers, Interdependence and Bilateral Relations: The Case of the Tuna War between the United States and Mexico., 1983 (Box 9)
  - Milicevic, Katarina, Mediation and Peacemaking in the Former Yugoslavia 1992-1995., 1997 (Box 34)
  - Minzner, Carl, United Nations Peacekeeping Forces 1956-1994. (Box 26)
  - Miramontes, Victor, A Bi-national view of Mexican Contract Labor in the United States: The role of the Bracero in the Economies of Mexico and the United States., 1975 (Box 1)
  - Morgan, Amanda Lynn, The State Institutionalization of Women's Issues: A Case Study of Chile's SERNAM., 1996 (Box 31)
  - Morrison, Catherine A., International Integration in the Small Scale: The Juárez-El Paso Border Community., 1995 (Box 28)
  - Moulton, Peter, Oil Wealth and Agriculture in Nigeria., 1982 (Box 7)
  - Murray, Britton, French Educational Decentralization and the European 'Common Regionalist Process'., 1992 (Box 22)
  - Nelson, Mark A., The Foreign Press in the Developing World: The Asean Case Study., 1980 (Box 5)
  - Nelson, Rachel, The Neoconservatives and the Conservative Coalition: Reviving the Cold War Consensus., 1997 (Box 34)
  - Nelson, Roy C., Heifer Project International's Relationships with its Counterparts in Belize, Honduras, and Mexico., 1983 (Box 9)
  - Netzer, Baïe, Sectoral Transformation in the West German Economy, Effects on the West German Job Market and Prospects for Foreign Workers., 1987 (Box 13)
  - Ng, Shiow May, A Comparative Study of Female Genital Mutilation in Kenya and Sudan., 1995 (Box 28)
  - Ngan, Judy, The International and Domestic Politics of Japan's Failure to Assume Responsibility on the "Comfort Women" Issue., 1999 (Box 38)
  - Niksic, Orphan, The Efficacy of Economic Statecraft in Peace-Building: The Case of Bosnia., 1998 (Box 36)
  - Norton, Donna, The Social and Economic Causes of Rural-to-Urban Migration in Nigeria., 1986 (Box 11)
  - O'Donnell, Bradley Thomas, National Income Accounting Reform: The Mexican Possibility., 1994 (Box 26)
  - Ooten, Chris, Japanese Investment in Southeast Asia: An Analysis of The Electronics Industries in Malaysia and Thailand., 1995 (Box 28)
  - Pahre, Robert, The American Relief Administration and Soviet Russia: 1919-1923., 1984 (Box 9)
  - Park, Eun, Joint Venture Opportunities in the People's Republic of China., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Parsons, Craig A., Ending the Ambiguities: French Security Policy and Franco-German Security Cooperation., 1992 (Box 22)
  - Pascoe, William, Genius Taming Friction's Lion: American and German Fighting Doctrine in World War Two., 1991 (Box 19)
  - Pearson, April, The GATT Government Procurement Code in the United States, the European Community, and Japan: A Case Study of United States Trade Policy and International Institutions., 1991 (Box 19)
  - Peer, Mary Megan, American Foreign Policy and American Foreign Investment: Does one serve the other?., 1999 (Box 38)
  - Peltz, Maxwell S., Costa Rica and the Reagan Administration: Sparring with a Giant., 1989 (Box 15)
  - Perkins, Lucy Fitch, Ethnic Chinese in Southeast Asia: Dilemmas of Race and Culture., 1987 (Box 13)
  - Pessoa, Ana Paula Machado, The Political and Economic Reasons for the Failure of the Cruzado Plan., 1991 (Box 19)
  - Peterson, L.T., THE SLOVENIANS OF CARINTHIA: A Transnational Minority Problem., 1975 (Box 1)
  - Pfeister, Doug, The Promotion of Democracy and United States Policy toward Haiti, 1985-1992., 1993 (Box 24)
  - Phan, Pamela, Sustaining a Communist Regime: Vietnam's Path from Institutionalization of the Chinese Model to Development of an alternative and Independent Vietnamese Model., 1997 (Box 34)
  - Pieslak, Sylvia, Wolnosc I Pokoj: "Freedom and Peace" Movement- A Transnational Social Movement At Its Best., 1999 (Box 38)
  - Pike, Sarah, From Protectionism to Free Trade: Structural Economic Adjustment and Deregulation...A Case Study of the Canadian Grape and Wine Industries., 1990 (Box 18)
  - Pitchford, Mark B., A Case Analysis: U.S.-Soviet Crisis Prevention in Afghanistan., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Pollard, Justin, "Environmental Impact Statements, World Bank Development Projects and the North American Free Trade Agreement"., 1996 (Box 31)
  - Porat, Ruth M., Nuclear Fuel Supply Assurances: The Link between Energy Security and the Nonproliferation of Nuclear Weapons., 1979 (Box 4)
  - Porges, Jennifer Lee, China's Changing Political Structure: An Assessment of the Impact of The Returned Scientists., 1987 (Box 13)
  - Prusia, Tiffany Jane, Why Peron? An Assessment of Explanations for the First Peronist Regime in Argentina (1943-55)., 1989 (Box 16)
  - Rachal, Denise, The Role of U.S. Foreign Policy in the Determination of Postwar Poland., 1991 (Box 19)
  - Rampton, Lisa Maren, Contested Religious Space and Time in the Reconstruction of Historical Memory: Conflict and Juxtaposition at the Tomb of the Patriarchs., 1996 (Box 31)
  - Reid, Robert H., The Relations Between Israel's Government and its National Institutions., 1988 (Box 14)
  - Relan, Rohit, The Politics and Economics of the Euro: Political Attitudes Towards Economic and Monetary Union in Britain and France Since 1989 and Their Effects on Business Interests., 1998 (Box 36)
  - Reta, Rodrigo Villarreal, The United Fruit Company in Costa Rica, 1957-1987: A Case Study of Returned Value of Investment"., 1990 (Box 18)
  - Rice, Angela J., Economic Development, Expectations and Efficiency: The Iberian Expansion of the European Community., 1995 (Box 27)
  - Richardson, Eric Nathan, Monopoly of Truth, Monopoly of Power: The Media's Role in Polish Political Dissent Since Solidarity., 1988 (Box 14)
  - Ricketts, Anita C., The Friend of my Enemy is my Enemy: U.S.-Saudi-Egyptians Relations 1955-1960., 1992 (Box 22)
  - Riddle, Jennifer, Hyphenated American Political Activity and U.S. Foreign Policy-Making., 1997 (Box 34)
  - Ringel, Allan William Jr., Globalization of the International System., 1993 (Box 24)
  - Ritchie, Lorelei D., Sovereignty and Despair in Post-Invasion Panama (1990-1993): Origins and Manifestation of Domestic Reactions following "Dynamic Subordination Theory". (Box 24)
  - Roberts, Andrew Joseph, Southeast Asia's Airline Industry: A Survey in Government Policy., 1998 (Box 36)
  - Rodriguez, Dorena L., The Reagan Doctrine and Pakistan., 1988 (Box 14)
  - Rosenfeld, Amy, Japan's Battle Against Air Pollution: A Case Study in Conflict Resolution., 1991 (Box 20)
  - Ross, Kelly, The Gaullist Heritage: Neo-Gaullism and European Defense., 1985 (Box 11)
  - Rowghani, Ali, The Search for a New Consensus: German Foreign Policy Since Reunification., 1996 (Box 31)
  - Rubenstein, Deborah, The Lavi Project: A Critique of American Jews' 'Blind Support' of Israel., 1989 (Box 16)
  - Rubio, Martha Elena, Human Rights and Political Transitions to Democracy in Latin America: Partial Truth and Little Justice., 1991 (Box 20)
  - Russell, Lynn M., Brown Coal in the Energy Policy of the German Democratic Republic: Environmental Values in Transition., 1991 (Box 20)
  - Ruthrauff, Holly M., Ethnic Conflict and International Response: Lessons from the Former Yugoslavia., 1995 (Box 27)
  - Sabry, Jamillah Kamillah, Lafanmi Selavi Home for Street Children Raising Social Consciousness Among Haiti's Youth., 1998 (Box 36)
  - Sanders, John Brinkley, Nuclear Proliferation in the 90s., 1995 (Box 28)
  - Savage, Nancy, The Lomé Convention: A Contribution to a New Economic World Order?., 1980 (Box 5)
  - Scarborough, Larry, The Basic Human Needs Strategy of Foreign Assistance: Will the Commitment Facilitate Success?., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Schlangen, Charles N. W., ...And in with the New; A Comparative Study of New Private Universities in Chile and Colombia., 1996 (Box 31)
  - Schmedemann, Deborah A., La Reve et le Reel Entrelaces: The Politics- Culture Nexus in Quebec Nationalism., 1977 (Box 1)
  - Schrader Jr., Robert E., The Collapse of Abgrenzung., 1991 (Box 20)
  - Schwartz, Skip, Challenges and Changes Facing German Labor Unions Since 1989., 1995 (Box 29)
  - Scott, William, Televised Adult Education and Rural Development in the Ivory Coast., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Selim, Mona, The Effectiveness of the Mass Media in Promoting the Egyptian National Family Planning Program., 1993 (Box 24)
  - Shah, Atman P., Gujarat and India: The Shift From Curative to Preventative Health Services., 1994 (Box 27)
  - Shalaby, Mark Alexander, The Economic Battlefield: Egyptian-Israeli Relations Since Camp David., 1994 (Box 26)
  - Shallman, Mary, Perspectives on World Order Reform., 1980 (Box 5)
  - Shapiro, Susanna, Movimento dos Trabalhadores Rurais Sem Terra (The Landless Workers Movement): Consolidating Brazil's Democracy Through the Struggle for Land., 1998 (Box 36)
  - Shen, Ing-ie Ava, Democracy on Trial: Agenda of the Student Movement in Postwar West Germany., 1992 (Box 22)
  - Sherman, Craig, The French Left and the Polish Crisis of 1980-81: "Une Affaire Interieure Francaise?"., 1985 (Box 11)
  - Shore, Marci, The Sacred and the Myth: Power, Ideology and Dissent in Normalization-era Czechoslovakia., 1994 (Box 26)
  - Sinnock, Ryan B., Japanese Investment in Southeast Asia: Problems and Possibilities., 1993 (Box 24)
  - Slain, Morgan D., The Struggle for Unity: Economic Crisis in Eastern Germany., 1991 (Box 20)
  - Slucter, Amy, Metaphors of Modernity: Women in the work of Frits Lang, Otto Dix, and Bertolt Brecht., 1998 (Box 36)
  - Smith, Amanda, Refugee Crisis Management: The Factors Which Determine Success and Failure., 1997 (Box 34)
  - Smith, Cedric L., Senagalese Labor Migration to France., 1979 (Box 4)
  - Smith, Celia Langdeau, The Economic Policies of the Italian Communist Party: Their Implications for American Foreign Direct Investment., 1979 (Box 4)
  - Smith, Martin Scott, Motivations of America Foreign Aid: A Study of the Allocation of U.S. Bilateral Development Assistance in the Early 1970's., 1979 (Box 4)
  - Stanley, William B., Determinants of Success in Promoting Participatory Community Development on a Wide Scale: A case study of Private Voluntary Organizations in Indonesia., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Stone, Jeffrey E., The Italian Communist Party and the Ideology of Eurocommunism., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Stromberg, Kristen, The Sociotechnical Shaping of International Collaboration in Scientific Research: A Case Study of the European Southern Observatory., 1994 (Box 27)
  - Talkington, Wade B., Internal Liberian Politics and U.S. Direct Investment (1925-1971)., 1988 (Box 14)
  - Tapia, Vanessa Elisa, Mexico and the North American Free Trade Agreement: The Effects of Foreign Direct Investment., 1994 (Box 27)
  - Tayyarah, Hala, Operation Lifeline Sudan: searching for modalities., 1995 (Box 29)
  - Thamkittikasem, Trin Jeff, Institutions and Organizations: The Influence of the United Nations in the Cambodian Peace Process., 1998 (Box 37)
  - Thaver, Komail Zulfikar, The State and Industrial Policy in Development: The South Korean Experience, 1962-82., 1993 (Box 24)
  - Thompson, G. Nanette, Seabed Resource Development: A Legal, Political and Economic Analysis., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Thuss, Charles J., III, The obstacles to a Market, Democratic Revolution: The Role of the Directors of Industry in Contemporary Russia., 1994 (Box 27)
  - Toliver, Carol, Regulation of the Euro-Currency Markets., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Townsend, Yolanda M., The U.S./Iran Hostage Crisis: A Case Study of Modern Coercive Diplomacy and Negotiation., 1983 (Box 9)
  - Tran, Ngoc B., The Emergence of a New Asian Tiger: An Examination of Vietnam's Economic Policies and Development Strategy., 1998 (Box 37)
  - Tripp, Alan, Sino-American Relations and the Chinese Atomic Energy Program., 1985 (Box 11)
  - Tsai, Lily, Village Governments, Property Rights, and Rural Industrialization: Accounting for Variation in Ownership Forms of Chinese Rural Enterprises., 1996 (Box 31)
  - Turkeltaub, Alex, Organized Alternatives to State Power: Original and Contemporary Developments., 1999 (Box 38)
  - Uribarri, Laura Margarita, The Paso del Norte Air Quality Task Force: A Case Study in Binational Cooperation., 1996 (Box 32)
  - Vachudová, Milanda Anna, Czechoslovak Foreign Policy: A New European Perspective., 1991 (Box 20)
  - Veale, Noelle Alejandra, The Decline of Rio de Janeiro: Analysis of a City without a Function., 1989 (Box 16)
  - Veninga, Karen, The PCF in the Eurocommunist Years: An Interlude in French Communist History., 1980 (Box 5)
  - von der Lippe, Sarah, The United States Agency for International Development and the Sahel, 1970 through 1974., 1985 (Box 11)
  - Walji, Iqbal, The Argument for Land Reform: A Case Study of Pakistani Land Reforms., 1980 (Box 5)
  - Wang, Jenny, The Hong Kong Handover: Taiwan's Lesson in Chinese Reunification., 1998 (Box 37)
  - Wang, Laure L., Japanese Trade, Investment, and Technology Transfer in Asia: A case study of the Japan-Korea and Japan-Thailand relationship and the shortcomings of dependency theory., 1992 (Box 22)
  - Waring, Nathaniel, The Continuity of Control: British Orientalism in U.S. Foreign Policy Towards India., 1986 (Box 11)
  - Warmbrunn, Susan Michele, Alienable Rights-Between Freedom and Control: The American Institute for Free Labor Development in El Salvador., 1990 (Box 20)
  - Watanabe, Saferi, The Road to Equality in the Workplace: The Challenges Women Face in Contemporary Japan., 1991 (Box 20)
  - Watson, Andrew, The Sacrifice of Okinawa and the Future of the U.S.-Japan Security Agreement., 1996 (Box 32)
  - Weale, Dianne Lee, Fortress Europe? Protection and Competition in the European Automobile Market., 1991 (Box 21)
  - Webster, Charles A., Catalan Nationalism and the Spanish State: Evaluating Accommodation., 1986 (Box 11)
  - Weigelt, Jörn, The Consequences of German Unification for Economic and Political Integration in Europe., 1991 (Box 21)
  - Werner, Michael E., Japanese--American Relations Leading to Pearl Harbor., 1982 (Box 8)
  - Whitaker, Anne, The Changing Political Position of Women in Russia and the Soviet Union: From perestroika to the parliamentary elections of 1993., 1995 (Box 29)
  - Williams, Don S., Patterns of Ineptitude: Trade Impacting Subsidies in the Post War Era., 1988 (Box 16)
  - Winden, Andrew, A Yen for Giving: Japanese Technical Cooperation in Thailand., 1990 (Box 18)
  - Witt, Michael A., A Comparative Analysis of the German and the Japanese Social Security Systems., 1995 (Box 29)
  - Wood, Bill, Argentine Economic Development Through 1955: An Examination of Resource Allocation and Structural Evolution., 1988 (Box 14)
  - Wood, Donna Christine, Perspectives on a New World Information Order., 1985 (Box 11)
  - Woolley, Roberta, Caught Up in the Dizziness of Reform; An Analysis of Political Strategy in Russia's Privatization Process., 1996 (Box 32)
  - Wright, Donald A., Israel and South Africa: Ideology and RealPolitik in the Creation of Regional Powers., 1988 (Box 14)
  - Wu, Clara M., The Role of Foreign Aid in Sino-Japanese Relations., 1988 (Box 14)
  - Yang, Chi-hui, Modernizing Ethnic Conflict: Population Transfers to the Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region of China, 1949-Present., 1998 (Box 37)
  - Yang, Julia Tzu-ye, Democratization and Political Identity in Taiwan: A Case Study On the 1998 Taipei Mayoral Election. (Box 38)
  - York, Peter A., Degrees of Success and Economic Integration in the Developing World: A Comparative Analysis of the Economic Community of West African States and the Association of Southeast Asian Nations., 1997 (Box 34)
  - York, Wendy Lee, Arab Investment and Influence in American Universities...Is There Cause For Concern?., 1980 (Box 6)
  - Yu, Maryling, Land and Fertility in Rural China: Analysis and Policy Perspectives., 1994 (Box 27)
  - Zajac, Jason M., "Tools of the Trade" The Structural and Impediments Initiative and its Impact on the Japanese Market., 1992 (Box 22)
  - Zimmerman, S. Rebecca, Significant Differences in the Physical Protection of Nuclear Materials: A Comparative Study., 1998 (Box 37)
  - Zuber, Paul, Socioeconomic Characteristics of Mexican Workers in the Cannery Industry in the Santa Clara Valley: A Comparative Study of Undocumented and Citizen/Resident Workers., 1982 (Box 8)
- Theses, 1993-2003; Accession ARCH_2011_152
  - Austin, Jonathan, The European Union in regional empowerment., undated (Box 2)
  - Eifert, Benn P., The political economy of economic management in postcolonial Zambia, 1964-2002., [2003] (Box 2)
  - Elias, Rebecca J., Creating corporate responsibility in Ecuador's oil industry: the influence of advocacy networks., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Chen, Julie, The French juvenile justice system: the Ordinance of 1945 in the 1990s., 2003 (Box 2)
  - Garrett, Kenneth, The International Olympic Committee and the German question: a case study of the role of transnational organizations in the international system., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Kaiser, Kai-Alexander, Post-colonial pathologies: ethnic regimes and Rentier states in the independent Guianas., 1993 (Box 1)
  - Kaske, Clea Katharina, A global road to justice? An organizational and institutional comparison between the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia and the International Criminal Court and the impact of US involvement in both cases., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Lee, Jeffrey, The failure of political Islam in Indonesia: why the world's largest Muslim-populated nation has never had Islamic government., 2003 (Box 2)
  - Maghzi, Shahla, Approaching the middle way: the relative decline of mediation and rise of litigation in contemporary China., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Manzano, Jorge Rafael, Modernizing basic education: considerations on Mexico's education decentralization policy and the effects of its administrative impacts., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Milk, Roberto, The Peruvian tax reform of the nineties: the steps to success., 1995 (Box 2)
  - Nadel, Sara, An investigation of the effects of dollarization on the economic welfare of Ecuador's poor., 2003 (Box 2)
  - Neril, Jonathan, Genetically modified corn in Oaxaca, Mexico: implications for indigenous communities, biodiversity, and international trade., 2003 (Box 2)
  - Person, Robert, Whither Russia? An analysis of Russian foreign poilicy under Vladimir Putin., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Schlangen, Charles N. W., … and in with the new: a comparative study of new private universities in Chile and Colombia., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Stan, Andreea, Anchoring inflation in transition economies: the case for a currency board arrangement in Romania., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Steinberg, Matthew M., A flawed approach to state building: the Office of the High Representative in Bosnia and Herzegovina., 2003 (Box 2)
  - Samarasinghe, Leshika, Why peoplization? Understanding the Sri Lankan decision to privatize., 2003 (Box 2)
  - Tan, Yeling, Women's empowerment through microfinance: evidence from Nepal and Bangladesh., 2002 (Box 2)
  - Yeh, Jocelyn, The law and practice of foreign direct investment in China., 1999 (Box 2)
- Theses, 2000; ARCH_2007_048
  - Andronache, Christina, Scapegoating Ideologies: Denial, Anti-Semitism and Nationalism in the Treatment of the Romanian Holocaust., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Arulanantham, David P., Domestic Concerns and Foreign policy: Indian involvement in Sri Lanka's ethnic conflict, 1983-1987., June 2000 (Box 1)
  - Chan, Nicholas M., Political Liberalization and Market Reform in Post-Mao China: The Mobilization of Civil Society., May 2000 (Box 1)
  - Dorobantu, Ruxandra, Nation, Nationalism and Ethnic Relations in Romania: Change and Continuity., 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - Feler, Leo, Growth and Empowerment: Strategies to Alleviate Poverty in Brazil., 2001 (Box 1)
  - Harris, Cody S., The Politics of Cohesion: An Investigation into the Transnational political groups of the European parliament., June 2000 (Box 1)
  - Larson, Abby, Mulitcultural citizenship for France: Effects of European Integration and Human Rights on Secular national citizenship., Spring 2000 (Box 1)
  - Lavender, Jeanine, Analogical Reasoning in the Kosovo Conflict., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Lavinbuk, Ariel N., A Preference for Failure: Symbolic Action and the United Nations interim force in Lebanon., October 18, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Liu, Gordon, Privatization with Chinese Characteristics: Gradual, Diverse and Communist-led Economic Transition., May 12, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Ozobia, Nnenna, We Wear the Mask: Racial Stratification in Post-Revolutionary Cuba., 2000 (Box 211)
  - Sundaresan, Thaila, Understanding the Kerala Paradox: The Communist Impact on Social and Economic Development., May 12, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Svilik, Patricia, Drop by Drop: NGO Pressure on teh World Bank., 2000 (Box 2)
  - Torres, Kristin Anne, Health Care or Wealth Care? -- Mexican Healthcare Reform in a Time of Economic and Political Liberalization., May 12, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Van Dusen, Trudy, Populism in Mexico, 1935-1940: A macroeconomic evaluation of the Lazaro Cardenas Administration., 19 May 2000 (Box 2)
  - Weinberger, Daniel, The Local Consequences of Economic Change in Israel: An Examination of Contemporary Transformations in the Israeli Development Towns., May 15, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Weisiger, Alex, Continuity in German Foreign Policy: The Recognition of Croatia and Slovenia., May 12, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Zaltzman, Haim, Stealing the Yeast: The Theory of Modular Opportunism and the economic divergence of post-communist Hungary and Russia., [2000] (Box 3)
  - Zemitis, Martin, National Policy with Multi-cultural society? - Ethnic Integration and democratic transition in Latvia., May 12, 2000 (Box 3)
- Theses, 2001; Accession ARCH_2007_162
  - Al-Foudery, Mariam Ali, Elections, Islamism, and the Politics of Welfare in the Modern Middle East., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Joshua Bishop, Common Water and Common Ground: Transboundary Environmental Management on the U.S.-Mexican Border: A Case Study of the San Pedro River., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - Azimi, Negar, AIDS and Denial and South Africa: A Critical Analysis of Post-Apartheid South Africa's Mother to Child Transmission Policy and President Thabo Mbeki's Challenge to the HIV/AIDS Thesis., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - Barrera, Teresa, Pop Foriegn Policy: The Elian Gonzalez Case and the Cuban Trade Embargo., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - Brandenburg, Margot, Relative Outcomes of Microfinance: A Comparison of Urban and Rural Institutions in Sub-Saharan Africa. (Box 1)
  - Chang, Jennifer, Taiwan's National Health Insurance: The Relationship., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - Chang, William S.W., Settling the Chinese Bar: Lawyers and Legality in Contemporary China., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - Chen, Amy, U.S. Policy Towards Rwanda, Spring to Summer 1994: From Genocide to Cholera., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - Cheng, Stephanie S., Strategic Calculation or Political Blunder? Analyzing Chirac's Decision to Dissolve the National Assembly in 1997 in the Context of Retrospective Voting and Blame Avoidance., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Galsterer, Victoria, Political Fission: The Nuclear Energy Controversy in France and Germany., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Greig, Fiona, Women's Empowerment and HIV Prevention in Botswana., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Hsu, Deanne Rosalyne, Factionalism and the Downfall of the KMT in the 2000 Taiwan Presidential Election., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Tressa, How Size Affects NGDO Learning and Evaluation Processes: A Cast Study Analysis., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Joyal, Roxanne, Class and Gender at the Crossroads: economic vulnerability among rural Kikuyu women: a case study of Ol Moran, Kenya., May 2001 [?2000] (Box 2)
  - Kapur, Vikas, India's Intervention in Sri Lanka: The Electoral Connection., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Lee, Chris, Korea and Tanzania: Case Studies in Leadership, State Intervention, and Economic Development., May 2001 (Box 2)